[
    {
    "ques_no": "1",
        "question":"Which of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "a":"Object-oriented",
        "b":"Use of pointers",
        "c":"Portable",
        "d":"Dynamic",
        "correct":"b",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "2",
        "question":"What is the size of an int variable in java?",
        "a":"4 bytes",
        "b":"2 bytes",
        "c":"8 bytes",
        "d":"Depends on the system",
        "correct":"a",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "3",
        "question":"Which method is the entry point of Java program?",
        "a":"start()",
        "b":"main()",
        "c":"run()",
        "d":"init",
        "correct":"b",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "4",
        "question":"Which of the following is used to handle exceptions in Java?",
        "a":"catch",
        "b":"throw",
        "c":"try",
        "d":"All of the above",
        "correct":"d",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "5",
        "question":"Java is a ___________ language",
        "a":"Compiled",
        "b":"interpreted",
        "c":"Both Compiled and interpreted",
        "d":"None of the above",
        "correct":"c",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "6",
        "question":"Which of these is not a valid data type in java?",
        "a":"int",
        "b":"float",
        "c":"real",
        "d":"boolean",
        "correct":"c",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "7",
        "question":"Which of the following loops in Java is entry-controlled?",
        "a":"do-while",
        "b":"while",
        "c":"both A and B",
        "d":"none",
        "correct":"b",
        "answer":"e"
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "8",
        "question":"What is the default value of a local variable in java?",
        "a":"0",
        "b":"null",
        "c":"Depends on the data type",
        "d":"No default value (must be initialized)",
        "correct":"d",
        "answer":"e"
        
    },
    {
        "ques_no": "9",
        "question":"Which of these keywords is used to define a class in Java?",
        "a":"define",
        "b":"class",
        "c":"object",
        "d":"void",
        "correct":"b",
        "answer":"e"
        

    },
    {
        "ques_no": "10",
        "question":"Which method is used to start a thread in Java?",
        "a":"run()",
        "b":"start()",
        "c":"execute()",
        "d":"init()",
        "correct":"b",
        "answer":"e"
        
    }
]